¬
{AMERICA_DISCOVERED_BODY}Testing the theory that one can head east by sailing west carried the risk of a remote, watery grave. Yet this act of courage has been rewarded with the discovery of a strange new land... perchance a whole new world. Who knows what riches await those with the courage to explore.
{AMERICA_DISCOVERED_TITLE}New World Discovered
{AZTECS_CONTACTED_BODY}It seems the new world is already dominated by an ancient culture - the Aztecs. For a seemingly simple people, their cities are vast and complicated. Their primitive outlook belies their ability to raise vast stone structures that rival anything the old world has to offer. And if gold is the measure of an Empire's might, then the Aztecs are formidable indeed.
{AZTECS_CONTACTED_TITLE}New World Inhabited
{BLACK_DEATH_1_BODY}The dire plague that scholars have now dubbed "The Great Mortality" is continuing its destructive trail through the west. Is the end truly nigh? Is this our judgement, and has the almighty finally decided that we are all too wretched to live?!
{BLACK_DEATH_1_TITLE}The Great Mortality
{BLACK_DEATH_2_BODY}Life in the civilised world has become more morbid and bleak than in known history. Every man woman and child is accustomed to the sight of their people stacked in piles before being burned... In the vain hope that the fires may cleanse this foul doom from the land.\n\nAlthough not everyone is falling victim to its deadly embrace, the plague is still decimating the population everywhere it travels.
{BLACK_DEATH_2_TITLE}The Great Mortality Spreads
{BLACK_DEATH_3_BODY}While the lands that were first stricken by the Great Mortality are beginning to discover a life beyond the plague, many places that had been spared this doom are now feeling its full effects.\n\nThough talk of this truly being the end is becoming less likely with enough survivors to prove the point, this creeping doom is still the most feared thing to stalk the lands of Europe for even the bravest of men, being dubbed "The Black Death" these days.
{BLACK_DEATH_3_TITLE}The Great Mortality Continues
{BLACK_DEATH_4_BODY}It would appear that the Black Death has worked most of its deadly misery upon the world, and that men of all faiths may have reason to make a prayer of thanks... We have been delivered!\n\nAside from some unfortunate destinations at the end of the major trade routes where the plague is a more recent tyrant, the risk of contracting the Black Death appears to now be negligible. Now those who rule the survivors may struggle over what remains of civilisation.
{BLACK_DEATH_4_TITLE}The Black Death Passes
{BLACK_DEATH_HITS_BODY}A plague of unfathomable proportions has made its way westward from the Far East, where it is said to have already ended an untold number of lives. The victims find their skin covered in dark blotches, as they enter a terrible fever and sickness which ultimately leads to a painful and miserable death.\n\nWhile scholars, theologians and physicians cannot agree on the exact cause of this deadly plague, the threat it poses men of all faiths is plain for all to see.
{BLACK_DEATH_HITS_TITLE}A Most Dreaded Plague
{EARTHQUAKE_IN_ALEPPO_BODY}The people of Aleppo have suffered terribly, as the very earth beneath the city and surrounding lands buckled and broke in what could only be described as a terrible act of divine wrath or punishment - tremors were felt all throughout. After such a cataclysmic event, Aleppo will take many years to recover fully.
{EARTHQUAKE_IN_ALEPPO_TITLE}Disaster Strikes Aleppo!
{EARTHQUAKE_IN_ALEXANDRIA_2_BODY}Those at Alexandria that lived to remember the last earthquake that ravaged the city have now had to endure this destructive nightmare twice! The people of this city can still take hope in the defiant survival of the Lighthouse, though its now huge wounds are a stark reminder of this place's misfortune.
{EARTHQUAKE_IN_ALEXANDRIA_2_TITLE}Alexandria Suffers Again!
{EARTHQUAKE_IN_ALEXANDRIA_BODY}An earthquake has shaken the entire eastern Mediterranean basin, most terribly so at the ancient city of Alexandria. Lives were lost in the ensuing chaos and destruction caused by falling buildings. Even the great Lighthouse that has stood for over a millennia bears scars from the tremendous power of the quake.
{EARTHQUAKE_IN_ALEXANDRIA_TITLE}Earthquake in Alexandria!
{EARTHQUAKE_IN_NAPLES_BODY}Sitting in the shadow of Vesuvius, the people of Naples have always known that they have lived with the constant threat of danger. However, the terrible earthquake that has recently brought down countless buildings and ended many lives is probably not the disaster they expected to befall them.
{EARTHQUAKE_IN_NAPLES_TITLE}Napoli Endures Earthquake!
{EARTHQUAKE_IN_SILICIA_BODY}A mighty earthquake has struck in the region of Silicia with damage being felt as far as way as Iconium. Fortunately the centre of the destructive power wasn't so close to this major population centre, although the casualties in the region have still been significant.
{EARTHQUAKE_IN_SILICIA_TITLE}Silicia Suffers Quake!
{FIRST_BLAST_FURNACE_BODY}A new way of working metal is now being practised in the village of Lapphyttan in Sweden, and adopted in western Europe. Housed in a great building, mighty water-driven bellows blast air into a furnace that produces a blaze so fierce and unworldly that the iron from within the ore flows out as a stream of molten metal!\n\nEven though the raw iron that pours from this new furnace is very brittle, vast amounts of the stuff can be made with relative ease, which a learned smith can then easily treat to produce incredibly resilient weapons and armour.
{FIRST_BLAST_FURNACE_TITLE}Man-made Inferno!
{FIRST_EUROPEAN_PAPER_BODY}Word is spreading across Europe on a new medium... Written on pressed paper! What has been an expensive luxury imported from the Middle East and beyond has now come to western Europe.\n\nA small mill devoted to pressing paper into sheets has been established in Xativa, south of Valencia. Although the ongoing Reconquista suggests that Islam is not welcome in Iberia, it is evident that some Muslim culture and innovations definitely are.
{FIRST_EUROPEAN_PAPER_TITLE}European Paper
{FIRST_EYEGLASSES_BODY}Reports are coming in from northern Italy of scholars placing delicate glass lenses in a thin metallic frame to be worn on the face. Apparently, if the lenses are made to the correct size they can help those with poor sight to see like normal, healthier citizens. Aesthetes among the scholarly community are concerned that wearing such a contraption will result in being teased or shunned.
{FIRST_EYEGLASSES_TITLE}Lucid Visions
{FIRST_MAGNETIC_COMPASS_BODY}It has been discovered that an ore from the Asia Minor region of Magnesia that attracts iron, also can make a piece of that metal orientate itself to point to the north - as reliably as a devout Muslim would turn to face Mecca.\n\nThis strange phenomena has been captured in a small device known as a 'compass' that cartographers and navigators have begun embracing in earnest, claiming it will take much of the guess work out of the art of exploration and map making.
{FIRST_MAGNETIC_COMPASS_TITLE}Scientific Breakthrough
{FIRST_MECHANICAL_CLOCK_BODY}An elaborate new time-measuring device has begun to appear in several places around Europe that does not rely upon water or the light of the sun to work. Scholars have explained that it has been discovered that the motion of a swinging object can be used to drive the 'clock' mechanism.\n\nThose that have seen one of these new mechanical clocks have suggested making one large enough to see from a distance would be useful.
{FIRST_MECHANICAL_CLOCK_TITLE}Time Machine Made
{FIRST_OIL_PAINTING_BODY}A Flemish painter, Jan van Eyck, is now championing an outlandish concept to produce paint created from seed oils rather than using tempera egg yolk. He claims that these 'oil paints' dry much more slowly, allowing the artist to take all the time needed to perfect each stroke and feature of their paintings.\n\nSome of the art establishment have declared that they are unconvinced as to the merits of oil paint, most likely because their specialised skills with tempera are about to become obsolete.
{FIRST_OIL_PAINTING_TITLE}Pioneer of Paint
{FIRST_PIANO_BODY}With the Papacy no longer denouncing polyphony, the musical technique where two melodies are united, we are now in an age where aspiring musical artists are pioneering new ways to make heavenly music.\n\nThe most recent advent in the musical world is an instrument known as a spinet. A true modern mechanical marvel, the spinet is driven by row of black and white keys, just like a pipe organ, that when pressed strike varying notes on strings cased within. The sounds it produces are not so powerful or profound as the pipe organ, making it something a wealthy noble or merchant could have in their home.
{FIRST_PIANO_TITLE}Portable Pipe Organ?
{FIRST_PRINTED_BIBLE_BODY}The same clergymen that were denouncing the printing press have now made a total about face, hailing Gutenburg as a spreader of the faith. The first book Gutenburg's printing company has been commissioned to publish is the Holy Bible itself.\n\nWhether this came about as a result of Gutenburg fearing retribution from the Papacy, or because the Catholic church is one of the few establishments wealthy enough to finance such a project matters little - Bibles will soon be readily accessible to the common man&  Even if he lacks the skills needed to read it.
{FIRST_PRINTED_BIBLE_TITLE}Papacy Pro-Printing
{FIRST_PRINTING_PRESS_BODY}News has arrived from Mainz that a goldsmith named Johann Gutenburg has invented a machine capable of repeatedly printing an entire page of the written word. Called the 'printing press', this machine has rows of slots that hold raised letters on tiny metal blocks. So long as the letters are properly arranged into words and sentences, it is then a simple matter of pressing the metallic type onto ink, and then paper to do in moments what takes a scribe considerable time.\n\nThere are some members of the cloth already claiming that the mass-production of books may result in widespread literacy, which will in turn lead to the unsupervised consumption of heretical beliefs.
{FIRST_PRINTING_PRESS_TITLE}The Mechanical Scribe!
{FIRST_PUBLIC_CLOCK_BODY}The citizens of the city of Milan can now claim to be the most punctual in the known world, or at least, their overseers and taskmasters can claim to know when their workers are tardy. An expensive mechanical clock has been set atop a tower, so that everyone from prince to pauper may see the time displayed from the city streets.\n\nTypically, now that scholars and engineers have succeeded in creating a truly grand mechanical clock, the more malcontent members of the noble class have begun calling for a portable version of the device!
{FIRST_PUBLIC_CLOCK_TITLE}Time for Everyone
{FIRST_RUDDER_BODY}Arabic sailors have successfully adopted an old seafaring trick from the Far East, using a plate of wood called a 'rudder' at the rear of a ship to change its path through the water.\n\nSome outlandish notions are being raised by some of the more eccentric military strategists that suggest that wars will one day be waged at sea, and that the rudder is a vital step toward their vision being realised.
{FIRST_RUDDER_TITLE}Seafaring Innovation
{FIRST_SAWMILL_BODY}Great minds have found new ways to make light of some of the heaviest work. Sawing wood has always been slow work for even the strongest labourers, but cunning engineers have found a way to drive a great saw capable of planing an entire log by using water!\n\n
{FIRST_SAWMILL_TITLE}The Forest is Conquered!
{FIRST_WATCH_BODY}At last an inventor has found a means to create a portable timepiece! Peter Henlein, a locksmith from Nuremberg has created a small clock being dubbed the 'Nuremberg Egg' for its oval shape. Once its spring mechanism inside its shell is wound, the 'egg' will display the hour, for almost two full days.\n\nDespite still being large enough to leave an incredibly unseemly lump in one's pocket, being seen in possession of one of Henlein's Nuremberg Eggs has become 'the' trinket to be seen to possess - for the few that can afford one.
{FIRST_WATCH_TITLE}Portable Clock
{FIRST_WHEELBARROW_BODY}Tales of a clever invention from the Far East have recently inspired European peasants to come up with a simple labourer's aid they are referring to as the 'wheelbarrow' .\n\nBy placing a wheel at the front of a wooden stretcher, it has been discovered that a lone worker can move a heavy load of stone on their own, with little risk of injury. It could be as much of a boon for lords seeking to raise castles in quick time, as it will be for the serfs who shall have to build them.
{FIRST_WHEELBARROW_TITLE}A Boon for Builders
{FIRST_WINDMILL_BODY}Reports are coming in from across Western Europe of engineers who have created a miracle mill that requires no stream or river to power it. Supposedly, man has found a way to let the very winds themselves drive massive mill mechanisms, simply by catching it in sails on beams of wood. While the Windmill's effectiveness reportedly dies as the winds do, to those living far from running water, it is sure to be considered a Godsend.
{FIRST_WINDMILL_TITLE}Making the Wind Work
{FOOTBALL_BANNED_BODY}The Lord Mayor of London has issued a proclamation of the banning of some violent mob behaviour that the commoners seem enamoured with...\n\n"And whereas there is a great uproar in the City through certain tumults arising from the striking of great footballs in the field of the public - from which many evils perchance may arise - which may God forbid - we do command and do forbid, on the King's behalf, upon pain of imprisonment, that such games shall not be practised henceforth within this city."\n\nNow that this law has been passed, the establishment are confident that these 'football' events have no chance of becoming an obsession of religious proportions.
{FOOTBALL_BANNED_TITLE}Football Denounced
{GROTE_MANDENKE_BODY}An incredible south-westerly Atlantic gale like never seen before has struck the north-western tip of Europe, lashing England, right across to Denmark. Unstoppable storm tides have swept inland, killing many, and conditions at sea are dire enough to make sailing for the brave and foolish only.
{GROTE_MANDENKE_TITLE}The Great Drowning of Men
{GUNPOWDER_DISCOVERED_BODY}A new discovery that could change the course of warfare - Gunpowder. This dark powder may look innocent enough, but when brought to spark it explodes with a force that is unmatched.\nThis terrible weapon will make armour obsolete, and render castle walls near useless. It would be wise to be the first to master its use in war.
{GUNPOWDER_DISCOVERED_TITLE}A Deadly New Weapon!
{MALLEUS_MALEFICARUM_BODY}In these dark times that see the Lord's children under constant exposure to heresy, and in extreme cases, witchcraft, at last we have been armed with the knowledge to drive back and defeat the forces of darkness - the Malleus Maleficarum, meaning, "The Hammer of Witches".\n\nThis tome has immediately been accepted as the definitive instruction set for a trial of heresy, covering everything from detecting witchcraft through to how to forcibly purge a human vessel of sin.
{MALLEUS_MALEFICARUM_TITLE}The Hammer of Witches'
{MONGOLS_INVASION_WARN_BODY}News has spread from merchants of the far east, who speak in great fear of a fierce warlord from Mongolia named Genghis Khan, who has amassed an unstoppable horde of cavalry. These Mongols are reportedly sweeping across Transoxania at a frightening rate, and look set on continuing westward, either north or south of the Caspian sea.
{MONGOLS_INVASION_WARN_TITLE}A New Threat!
{PLAYER_FIRST_HUGE_CATHEDRAL_BODY}If there were any lingering doubts as to the power of the church, they were dispelled once the people gazed upon God’s greatest house on earth. Its towering presence here shall ensure Christian dominance throughout the land.
{PLAYER_FIRST_HUGE_CATHEDRAL_TITLE}Worlds First Huge Cathedral
{PLAYER_FIRST_GREAT_JAMA_BODY}The Muslims do not worship symbols, for the prophet, blessed be his name, had decreed that to represent the divine with an icon or image is blasphemy in the extreme. However, nobody could really deny that the sight of this grand mosque serves as a shining example of the might and wisdom of Islam.
{PLAYER_FIRST_GREAT_JAMA_TITLE}First Great Jama
{JERUSALEM_CATHOLIC_BODY}By the Grace of God, those who went forth in the name our Lord have captured Jerusalem. Thus the Holy city has been triumphantly reclaimed in the name of Christ. All of Christendom will rejoice, for God's Children may now find salvation in the Kingdom of Heaven.
{JERUSALEM_CATHOLIC_TITLE}Jerusalem Captured
{JERUSALEM_ISLAM_BODY}Today the followers of the Prophet Mohammed rejoice. For Muslim armies have captured the Holy city of Jerusalem.
{JERUSALEM_ISLAM_TITLE}Jerusalem Captured
{SCIENCE_ALCHEMY_BOOK_BODY}Robert of Chester, an English translator has completed his transcription of the Liber de Compositione Alchemiae, or more simply, the Book of the Composition of Alchemy. Originally an Arabic text, this grand compendium of scientific and alchemical discoveries and musings is being deemed an affront to holy mandate by the establishment... But rumour has it most scholars would risk being associated with heretical beliefs to glean the knowledge hidden within its pages.
{SCIENCE_ALCHEMY_BOOK_TITLE}Liber de Compositione Alchemiae
{SCIENCE_DA_VINCI_ORNITHOPTER_BODY}Leonardo da Vinci, an Italian mastermind known for his revolutionary artistic works and ingenious inventions has concocted his most ambitious and eldritch design yet. His fascination with the science of flight has culminated in his 'Ornithopter' design.\n\nLooking something akin to a windmill sail atop a horseless carriage, many other scholars are laughing, suggesting da Vinci should go back to his concepts based upon attaching wings to the human body.
{SCIENCE_DA_VINCI_ORNITHOPTER_TITLE}Machines that Fly?
{SCIENCE_DE_DOCTA_IGNORANTIA_BODY}A Catholic scholar, Nicholas of Cusa has published a series of scientific and philosophical claims, bundled together under the somewhat arrogant title of De Docta Ignorantia - literally meaning, 'Of Learned Ignorance' .\n\nHis theories include the notion that the Earth is not the centre of the Universe, and that it actually orbits the Sun. Even more fantastical, he even attests that the stars of the night sky are actually distant suns themselves!
{SCIENCE_DE_DOCTA_IGNORANTIA_TITLE}Of Learned Ignorance
{SCIENCE_MATHS_ZERO_EUROPE_BODY}A mathematician from Pisa by the name of Fibonacci has published a new work entitled 'Liber Abaci'. He has adopted some Hindu-Arabic theories involving a number that has no value, claiming this is a vital step for making calculations on a grand scale.\n\nDespite managing to excite western scholars, the Liber Abaci's revelations offer few insights to the common man... who typically spends all his life dealing with things of 'no value'.
{SCIENCE_MATHS_ZERO_EUROPE_TITLE}The Hero of Zero
{SCIENCE_WEATHER_FORECAST_BODY}An aspiring English scholar by the name of Walter Merle claims that he is able to predict the weather - unlike the mystical ramblings of yesteryear's heretical pagans who claimed to have a spiritual insight into when the heavens will open up, Merle has stated he can do this simply by scientific observation.\n\nApparently Merle's predictions are correct more often than not, but his system is still being perfected. Surely it will only be a matter of months now before man knows exactly how the weather will behave.
{SCIENCE_WEATHER_FORECAST_TITLE}Bold Predictions
{THE_MONGOLS_EMERGE_BODY}It is easy to become comfortable with the enemy you know, our familiar foes. But to discount the menaces that lurk beyond the known world is to risk a rude awakening that can become a nightmare. This nightmare is the Mongol invasion.\nThe bulk of the Mongol forces have arrived not far from %S, making it a dangerous place at best now.
{THE_MONGOLS_EMERGE_TITLE}The Mongols Invade!
{THE_TIMURIDS_EMERGE_BODY}After facing the terror of the Mongol invasion, nobody would have dreamed that a serious peril could ever rise from the east again. However, Timur the Lame, a mighty warlord from Transoxania, has arrived on the eastern borders of our maps, bringing with him a legacy of conquest that cannot be ignored.\nHaving already conquered Persia, and distant India, Timur is certain to bring with him something exotic to show the people of the west. Something they will be sure to remember... as long as they live.\nThe mighty war machine of Timur the Lame has stormed into the lands surrounding %S.
{THE_TIMURIDS_EMERGE_TITLE}The Timurids Invade!
{TIMURIDS_INVASION_WARN_BODY}The Mongol invasion was a terror that the rulers of the western world were simply not ready to face, but if the stories of travellers are to be paid any heed then there is an even greater threat on its way!
{TIMURIDS_INVASION_WARN_TITLE}An Even Greater Threat?
{WORLD_IS_ROUND_BODY}First expressed by the ancient greeks, the scholars of the middle ages maintained the knowledge, that the world is round. Rumors and legends from the Vikings where told by the campfires, that there was new land in the west. But sailing across the watery desert of the atlantic is no easy venture. Many and more ships got blown of coastal waters, never to return. Maybe the time is right for adventurous men, to find a new trade route to the far east or even unknown riches and land. With the right ship and crew, a man could make a fortune.
{WORLD_IS_ROUND_TITLE}Terra Incognita
{WORLD_DOM_BODY}Well, alright laddie, you have brought peace to the world. \n\n Take a seat, have a cookie and think about new challenges.
{WORLD_DOM_TITLE}Pax Mundi 

{LITHUANIA_CONVERSION_BODY}“Excuse me sir, do you have a moment to talk about Jesus Christ? - Our Lord and Saviour would like to welcome you in our big, friendly family. He could even pop up on your parties, when you ran out of wine or bread. You would just have to eat his flesh and drink his blood, every sunday. And the rumours about him being a zombie, because he rose from the dead are just hearsay. He would never eat your brain. So...? Would you like to convert? It may convince some people in Europe to stop those small crusades against you. And you could go on a little rampage in the middle east. It is a win win situation, isn't it? 
{LITHUANIA_CONVERSION_TITLE}Accept Our Lord and Saviour
{LITHUANIA_CONVERTS_BODY}The Lithuanians, the last heathens in Europe, have made a wise decision. They accepted Christ as their Lord and Saviour. Hooray for the pope, rejoice and celebrate good times, comes on... na na na na na na na. 
{LITHUANIA_CONVERTS_TITLE}Catholicism Wow!

{MONGOLS_CONVERSION_BODY} "I bear witness that there is no object of adoration besides Allah, Who is One and has no associate and I bear witness that Muhammad is His servant and His Messenger." Well, sometimes you will have to please the conquered masses by converting to an appropriate god...
{MONGOLS_CONVERSION_TITLE}No God but One
{MONGOLS_CONVERTS_BODY}Most of the Mongol leaders have converted to Islam, because many of their subjects already worshiped the one and only Allah. Was a wise decision, wasn't it? 
{MONGOLS_CONVERTS_TITLE}Islam Wow!

{NORWAY_CONVERSION_BODY} "Odin let me die in battle!" \n\n It's your choice. Denounce Christianity and convert back to the olden ways of Viking glory or stay in Gods herd among the european kingdoms. \n\n Choose to go to Walhalla, but remember, there is no going back!
{NORWAY_CONVERSION_TITLE}Unto Walhalla 
{NORWAY_CONVERTS_BODY}
Those who thought the gods of old were gone and weak were proven wrong, as the King and the Jarls got convinced by the druids that the old Viking gods were still powerful, 
Odin and Thor swept with hammer and lightning through the kingdom and uprooted the christians. 
{NORWAY_CONVERTS_TITLE}Paganism Wow!


{PROTESTANTISM_WARNING_BODY}Word spreads rapidly that a german monk has came to view and teaches the use of terms such as penance and righteousness by the Catholic Church in new ways. He became convinced that the church is corrupt in its ways and had lost sight of what he saw as several of the central truths of Christianity. \n\n What could a single monk possibly achieve...
{PROTESTANTISM_WARNING_TITLE}Sola Fide 

{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_HRE_BODY}“This life therefore is not righteousness, but growth in righteousness, not health, but healing, not being but becoming, not rest but exercise. We are not yet what we shall be, but we are growing toward it, the process is not yet finished, but it is going on, this is not the end, but it is the road. All does not yet gleam in glory, but all is being purified.” \n\n Will you convert to Protestantism and abdict the false shine of Catholizism?
{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_HRE_TITLE}Follow Martin Luther
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_HRE_BODY}“I cannot choose but adhere to the word of God, which has possession of my conscience; nor can I possibly, nor will I even make any recantation, since it is neither safe nor honest to act contrary to conscience! Here I stand; I cannot do otherwise, so help me God! Amen.”
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_HRE_TITLE}Here I stand!

{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_ENGLAND_BODY}“This life therefore is not righteousness, but growth in righteousness, not health, but healing, not being but becoming, not rest but exercise. We are not yet what we shall be, but we are growing toward it, the process is not yet finished, but it is going on, this is not the end, but it is the road. All does not yet gleam in glory, but all is being purified.” \n\n Will you convert to Protestantism and abdict the false shine of Catholizism?
{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_ENGLAND_TITLE}Follow Martin Luther
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_ENGLAND_BODY}“I cannot choose but adhere to the word of God, which has possession of my conscience; nor can I possibly, nor will I even make any recantation, since it is neither safe nor honest to act contrary to conscience! Here I stand; I cannot do otherwise, so help me God! Amen.”
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_ENGLAND_TITLE}Here I stand!

{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_IRELAND_BODY}“This life therefore is not righteousness, but growth in righteousness, not health, but healing, not being but becoming, not rest but exercise. We are not yet what we shall be, but we are growing toward it, the process is not yet finished, but it is going on, this is not the end, but it is the road. All does not yet gleam in glory, but all is being purified.” \n\n Will you convert to Protestantism and abdict the false shine of Catholizism?
{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_IRELAND_TITLE}Follow Martin Luther
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_IRELAND_BODY}“I cannot choose but adhere to the word of God, which has possession of my conscience; nor can I possibly, nor will I even make any recantation, since it is neither safe nor honest to act contrary to conscience! Here I stand; I cannot do otherwise, so help me God! Amen.”
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_IRELAND_TITLE}Here I stand!

{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_SCOTLAND_BODY}“This life therefore is not righteousness, but growth in righteousness, not health, but healing, not being but becoming, not rest but exercise. We are not yet what we shall be, but we are growing toward it, the process is not yet finished, but it is going on, this is not the end, but it is the road. All does not yet gleam in glory, but all is being purified.” \n\n Will you convert to Protestantism and abdict the false shine of Catholizism?
{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_SCOTLAND_TITLE}Follow Martin Luther
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_SCOTLAND_BODY}“I cannot choose but adhere to the word of God, which has possession of my conscience; nor can I possibly, nor will I even make any recantation, since it is neither safe nor honest to act contrary to conscience! Here I stand; I cannot do otherwise, so help me God! Amen.”
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_SCOTLAND_TITLE}Here I stand!

{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_FRANCE_BODY}“This life therefore is not righteousness, but growth in righteousness, not health, but healing, not being but becoming, not rest but exercise. We are not yet what we shall be, but we are growing toward it, the process is not yet finished, but it is going on, this is not the end, but it is the road. All does not yet gleam in glory, but all is being purified.” \n\n Will you convert to Protestantism and abdict the false shine of Catholizism?
{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_FRANCE_TITLE}Follow Martin Luther
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_FRANCE_BODY}“I cannot choose but adhere to the word of God, which has possession of my conscience; nor can I possibly, nor will I even make any recantation, since it is neither safe nor honest to act contrary to conscience! Here I stand; I cannot do otherwise, so help me God! Amen.”
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_FRANCE_TITLE}Here I stand!

{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_SPAIN_BODY}“This life therefore is not righteousness, but growth in righteousness, not health, but healing, not being but becoming, not rest but exercise. We are not yet what we shall be, but we are growing toward it, the process is not yet finished, but it is going on, this is not the end, but it is the road. All does not yet gleam in glory, but all is being purified.” \n\n Will you convert to Protestantism and abdict the false shine of Catholizism?
{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_SPAIN_TITLE}Follow Martin Luther
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_SPAIN_BODY}“I cannot choose but adhere to the word of God, which has possession of my conscience; nor can I possibly, nor will I even make any recantation, since it is neither safe nor honest to act contrary to conscience! Here I stand; I cannot do otherwise, so help me God! Amen.”
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_SPAIN_TITLE}Here I stand!

{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_PORTUGAL_BODY}“This life therefore is not righteousness, but growth in righteousness, not health, but healing, not being but becoming, not rest but exercise. We are not yet what we shall be, but we are growing toward it, the process is not yet finished, but it is going on, this is not the end, but it is the road. All does not yet gleam in glory, but all is being purified.” \n\n Will you convert to Protestantism and abdict the false shine of Catholizism?
{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_PORTUGAL_TITLE}Follow Martin Luther
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_PORTUGAL_BODY}“I cannot choose but adhere to the word of God, which has possession of my conscience; nor can I possibly, nor will I even make any recantation, since it is neither safe nor honest to act contrary to conscience! Here I stand; I cannot do otherwise, so help me God! Amen.”
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_PORTUGAL_TITLE}Here I stand!

{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_VENICE_BODY}“This life therefore is not righteousness, but growth in righteousness, not health, but healing, not being but becoming, not rest but exercise. We are not yet what we shall be, but we are growing toward it, the process is not yet finished, but it is going on, this is not the end, but it is the road. All does not yet gleam in glory, but all is being purified.” \n\n Will you convert to Protestantism and abdict the false shine of Catholizism?
{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_VENICE_TITLE}Follow Martin Luther
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_VENICE_BODY}“I cannot choose but adhere to the word of God, which has possession of my conscience; nor can I possibly, nor will I even make any recantation, since it is neither safe nor honest to act contrary to conscience! Here I stand; I cannot do otherwise, so help me God! Amen.”
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_VENICE_TITLE}Here I stand!

{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_MILAN_BODY}“This life therefore is not righteousness, but growth in righteousness, not health, but healing, not being but becoming, not rest but exercise. We are not yet what we shall be, but we are growing toward it, the process is not yet finished, but it is going on, this is not the end, but it is the road. All does not yet gleam in glory, but all is being purified.” \n\n Will you convert to Protestantism and abdict the false shine of Catholizism?
{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_MILAN_TITLE}Follow Martin Luther
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_MILAN_BODY}“I cannot choose but adhere to the word of God, which has possession of my conscience; nor can I possibly, nor will I even make any recantation, since it is neither safe nor honest to act contrary to conscience! Here I stand; I cannot do otherwise, so help me God! Amen.”
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_MILAN_TITLE}Here I stand!

{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_SICILY_BODY}“This life therefore is not righteousness, but growth in righteousness, not health, but healing, not being but becoming, not rest but exercise. We are not yet what we shall be, but we are growing toward it, the process is not yet finished, but it is going on, this is not the end, but it is the road. All does not yet gleam in glory, but all is being purified.” \n\n Will you convert to Protestantism and abdict the false shine of Catholizism?
{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_SICILY_TITLE}Follow Martin Luther
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_SICILY_BODY}“I cannot choose but adhere to the word of God, which has possession of my conscience; nor can I possibly, nor will I even make any recantation, since it is neither safe nor honest to act contrary to conscience! Here I stand; I cannot do otherwise, so help me God! Amen.”
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_SICILY_TITLE}Here I stand!

{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_HUNGARY_BODY}“This life therefore is not righteousness, but growth in righteousness, not health, but healing, not being but becoming, not rest but exercise. We are not yet what we shall be, but we are growing toward it, the process is not yet finished, but it is going on, this is not the end, but it is the road. All does not yet gleam in glory, but all is being purified.” \n\n Will you convert to Protestantism and abdict the false shine of Catholizism?
{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_HUNGARY_TITLE}Follow Martin Luther
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_HUNGARY_BODY}“I cannot choose but adhere to the word of God, which has possession of my conscience; nor can I possibly, nor will I even make any recantation, since it is neither safe nor honest to act contrary to conscience! Here I stand; I cannot do otherwise, so help me God! Amen.”
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_HUNGARY_TITLE}Here I stand!

{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_POLAND_BODY}“This life therefore is not righteousness, but growth in righteousness, not health, but healing, not being but becoming, not rest but exercise. We are not yet what we shall be, but we are growing toward it, the process is not yet finished, but it is going on, this is not the end, but it is the road. All does not yet gleam in glory, but all is being purified.” \n\n Will you convert to Protestantism and abdict the false shine of Catholizism?
{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_POLAND_TITLE}Follow Martin Luther
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_POLAND_BODY}“I cannot choose but adhere to the word of God, which has possession of my conscience; nor can I possibly, nor will I even make any recantation, since it is neither safe nor honest to act contrary to conscience! Here I stand; I cannot do otherwise, so help me God! Amen.”
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_POLAND_TITLE}Here I stand!

{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_DENMARK_BODY}“This life therefore is not righteousness, but growth in righteousness, not health, but healing, not being but becoming, not rest but exercise. We are not yet what we shall be, but we are growing toward it, the process is not yet finished, but it is going on, this is not the end, but it is the road. All does not yet gleam in glory, but all is being purified.” \n\n Will you convert to Protestantism and abdict the false shine of Catholizism?
{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_DENMARK_TITLE}Follow Martin Luther
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_DENMARK_BODY}“I cannot choose but adhere to the word of God, which has possession of my conscience; nor can I possibly, nor will I even make any recantation, since it is neither safe nor honest to act contrary to conscience! Here I stand; I cannot do otherwise, so help me God! Amen.”
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_DENMARK_TITLE}Here I stand!

{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_NORWAY_BODY}“This life therefore is not righteousness, but growth in righteousness, not health, but healing, not being but becoming, not rest but exercise. We are not yet what we shall be, but we are growing toward it, the process is not yet finished, but it is going on, this is not the end, but it is the road. All does not yet gleam in glory, but all is being purified.” \n\n Will you convert to Protestantism and abdict the false shine of Catholizism?
{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_NORWAY_TITLE}Follow Martin Luther
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_NORWAY_BODY}“I cannot choose but adhere to the word of God, which has possession of my conscience; nor can I possibly, nor will I even make any recantation, since it is neither safe nor honest to act contrary to conscience! Here I stand; I cannot do otherwise, so help me God! Amen.”
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_NORWAY_TITLE}Here I stand!

{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_LITHUANIA_BODY}“This life therefore is not righteousness, but growth in righteousness, not health, but healing, not being but becoming, not rest but exercise. We are not yet what we shall be, but we are growing toward it, the process is not yet finished, but it is going on, this is not the end, but it is the road. All does not yet gleam in glory, but all is being purified.” \n\n Will you convert to Protestantism and abdict the false shine of Catholizism?
{PROTESTANT_CONVERSION_LITHUANIA_TITLE}Follow Martin Luther
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_LITHUANIA_BODY}“I cannot choose but adhere to the word of God, which has possession of my conscience; nor can I possibly, nor will I even make any recantation, since it is neither safe nor honest to act contrary to conscience! Here I stand; I cannot do otherwise, so help me God! Amen.”
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_LITHUANIA_TITLE}Here I stand!

{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_BODY}“I cannot choose but adhere to the word of God, which has possession of my conscience; nor can I possibly, nor will I even make any recantation, since it is neither safe nor honest to act contrary to conscience! Here I stand; I cannot do otherwise, so help me God! Amen.” \n\n A catholic nation has converted to protestantism.
{PROTESTANT_CONVERTS_TITLE}Here I stand!

{HRE_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, HRE spent too much on the army
{HRE_IDEBT_TITLE}HRE in debt
{HRE_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, HRE can continue to recruit now
{HRE_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}HRE back on track
{HRE_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, HRE still in debt
{HRE_SDEBT_TITLE}HRE still in debt
{HRE_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, HRE got money
{HRE_MDEBT_TITLE}HRE got Money

{ENGLAND_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, ENGLAND spent too much on the army
{ENGLAND_IDEBT_TITLE}ENGLAND in debt
{ENGLAND_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, ENGLAND can continue to recruit now
{ENGLAND_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}ENGLAND back on track
{ENGLAND_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, ENGLAND still in debt
{ENGLAND_SDEBT_TITLE}ENGLAND still in debt
{ENGLAND_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, ENGLAND got money
{ENGLAND_MDEBT_TITLE}ENGLAND got Money

{FRANCE_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, FRANCE spent too much on the army
{FRANCE_IDEBT_TITLE}FRANCE in debt
{FRANCE_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, FRANCE can continue to recruit now
{FRANCE_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}FRANCE back on track
{FRANCE_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, FRANCE still in debt
{FRANCE_SDEBT_TITLE}FRANCE still in debt
{FRANCE_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, FRANCE got money
{FRANCE_MDEBT_TITLE}FRANCE got Money

{SPAIN_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, SPAIN spent too much on the army
{SPAIN_IDEBT_TITLE}SPAIN in debt
{SPAIN_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, SPAIN can continue to recruit now
{SPAIN_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}SPAIN back on track
{SPAIN_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, SPAIN still in debt
{SPAIN_SDEBT_TITLE}SPAIN still in debt
{SPAIN_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, SPAIN got money
{SPAIN_MDEBT_TITLE}SPAIN got Money

{VENICE_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, VENICE spent too much on the army
{VENICE_IDEBT_TITLE}VENICE in debt
{VENICE_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, VENICE can continue to recruit now
{VENICE_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}VENICE back on track
{VENICE_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, VENICE still in debt
{VENICE_SDEBT_TITLE}VENICE still in debt
{VENICE_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, VENICE got money
{VENICE_MDEBT_TITLE}VENICE got Money

{SICILY_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, SICILY spent too much on the army
{SICILY_IDEBT_TITLE}SICILY in debt
{SICILY_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, SICILY can continue to recruit now
{SICILY_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}SICILY back on track
{SICILY_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, SICILY still in debt
{SICILY_SDEBT_TITLE}SICILY still in debt
{SICILY_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, SICILY got money
{SICILY_MDEBT_TITLE}SICILY got Money

{MILAN_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, MILAN spent too much on the army
{MILAN_IDEBT_TITLE}MILAN in debt
{MILAN_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, MILAN can continue to recruit now
{MILAN_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}MILAN back on track
{MILAN_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, MILAN still in debt
{MILAN_SDEBT_TITLE}MILAN still in debt
{MILAN_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, MILAN got money
{MILAN_MDEBT_TITLE}MILAN got Money

{SCOTLAND_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, SCOTLAND spent too much on the army
{SCOTLAND_IDEBT_TITLE}SCOTLAND in debt
{SCOTLAND_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, SCOTLAND can continue to recruit now
{SCOTLAND_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}SCOTLAND back on track
{SCOTLAND_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, SCOTLAND still in debt
{SCOTLAND_SDEBT_TITLE}SCOTLAND still in debt
{SCOTLAND_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, SCOTLAND got money
{SCOTLAND_MDEBT_TITLE}SCOTLAND got Money

{BYZANTIUM_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, BYZANTIUM spent too much on the army
{BYZANTIUM_IDEBT_TITLE}BYZANTIUM in debt
{BYZANTIUM_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, BYZANTIUM can continue to recruit now
{BYZANTIUM_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}BYZANTIUM back on track
{BYZANTIUM_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, BYZANTIUM still in debt
{BYZANTIUM_SDEBT_TITLE}BYZANTIUM still in debt
{BYZANTIUM_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, BYZANTIUM got money
{BYZANTIUM_MDEBT_TITLE}BYZANTIUM got Money

{RUSSIA_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, RUSSIA spent too much on the army
{RUSSIA_IDEBT_TITLE}RUSSIA in debt
{RUSSIA_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, RUSSIA can continue to recruit now
{RUSSIA_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}RUSSIA back on track
{RUSSIA_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, RUSSIA still in debt
{RUSSIA_SDEBT_TITLE}RUSSIA still in debt
{RUSSIA_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, RUSSIA got money
{RUSSIA_MDEBT_TITLE}RUSSIA got Money

{MOORS_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, MOORS spent too much on the army
{MOORS_IDEBT_TITLE}MOORS in debt
{MOORS_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, MOORS can continue to recruit now
{MOORS_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}MOORS back on track
{MOORS_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, MOORS still in debt
{MOORS_SDEBT_TITLE}MOORS still in debt
{MOORS_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, MOORS got money
{MOORS_MDEBT_TITLE}MOORS got Money

{TURKS_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, TURKS spent too much on the army
{TURKS_IDEBT_TITLE}TURKS in debt
{TURKS_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, TURKS can continue to recruit now
{TURKS_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}TURKS back on track
{TURKS_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, TURKS still in debt
{TURKS_SDEBT_TITLE}TURKS still in debt
{TURKS_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, TURKS got money
{TURKS_MDEBT_TITLE}TURKS got Money

{EGYPT_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, EGYPT spent too much on the army
{EGYPT_IDEBT_TITLE}EGYPT in debt
{EGYPT_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, EGYPT can continue to recruit now
{EGYPT_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}EGYPT back on track
{EGYPT_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, EGYPT still in debt
{EGYPT_SDEBT_TITLE}EGYPT still in debt
{EGYPT_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, EGYPT got money
{EGYPT_MDEBT_TITLE}EGYPT got Money

{DENMARK_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, DENMARK spent too much on the army
{DENMARK_IDEBT_TITLE}DENMARK in debt
{DENMARK_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, DENMARK can continue to recruit now
{DENMARK_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}DENMARK back on track
{DENMARK_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, DENMARK still in debt
{DENMARK_SDEBT_TITLE}DENMARK still in debt
{DENMARK_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, DENMARK got money
{DENMARK_MDEBT_TITLE}DENMARK got Money

{PORTUGAL_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, PORTUGAL spent too much on the army
{PORTUGAL_IDEBT_TITLE}PORTUGAL in debt
{PORTUGAL_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, PORTUGAL can continue to recruit now
{PORTUGAL_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}PORTUGAL back on track
{PORTUGAL_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, PORTUGAL still in debt
{PORTUGAL_SDEBT_TITLE}PORTUGAL still in debt
{PORTUGAL_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, PORTUGAL got money
{PORTUGAL_MDEBT_TITLE}PORTUGAL got Money

{POLAND_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, POLAND spent too much on the army
{POLAND_IDEBT_TITLE}POLAND in debt
{POLAND_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, POLAND can continue to recruit now
{POLAND_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}POLAND back on track
{POLAND_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, POLAND still in debt
{POLAND_SDEBT_TITLE}POLAND still in debt
{POLAND_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, POLAND got money
{POLAND_MDEBT_TITLE}POLAND got Money

{HUNGARY_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, HUNGARY spent too much on the army
{HUNGARY_IDEBT_TITLE}HUNGARY in debt
{HUNGARY_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, HUNGARY can continue to recruit now
{HUNGARY_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}HUNGARY back on track
{HUNGARY_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, HUNGARY still in debt
{HUNGARY_SDEBT_TITLE}HUNGARY still in debt
{HUNGARY_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, HUNGARY got money
{HUNGARY_MDEBT_TITLE}HUNGARY got Money

{PAPAL_STATES_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, PAPAL_STATES spent too much on the army
{PAPAL_STATES_IDEBT_TITLE}PAPAL_STATES in debt
{PAPAL_STATES_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, PAPAL_STATES can continue to recruit now
{PAPAL_STATES_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}PAPAL_STATES back on track
{PAPAL_STATES_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, PAPAL_STATES still in debt
{PAPAL_STATES_SDEBT_TITLE}PAPAL_STATES still in debt
{PAPAL_STATES_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, PAPAL_STATES got money
{PAPAL_STATES_MDEBT_TITLE}PAPAL_STATES got Money

{MONGOLS_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, MONGOLS spent too much on the army
{MONGOLS_IDEBT_TITLE}MONGOLS in debt
{MONGOLS_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, MONGOLS can continue to recruit now
{MONGOLS_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}MONGOLS back on track
{MONGOLS_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, MONGOLS still in debt
{MONGOLS_SDEBT_TITLE}MONGOLS still in debt
{MONGOLS_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, MONGOLS got money
{MONGOLS_MDEBT_TITLE}MONGOLS got Money

{TIMURIDS_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, TIMURIDS spent too much on the army
{TIMURIDS_IDEBT_TITLE}TIMURIDS in debt
{TIMURIDS_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, TIMURIDS can continue to recruit now
{TIMURIDS_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}TIMURIDS back on track
{TIMURIDS_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, TIMURIDS still in debt
{TIMURIDS_SDEBT_TITLE}TIMURIDS still in debt
{TIMURIDS_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, TIMURIDS got money
{TIMURIDS_MDEBT_TITLE}TIMURIDS got Money

{NORWAY_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, NORWAY spent too much on the army
{NORWAY_IDEBT_TITLE}NORWAY in debt
{NORWAY_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, NORWAY can continue to recruit now
{NORWAY_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}NORWAY back on track
{NORWAY_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, NORWAY still in debt
{NORWAY_SDEBT_TITLE}NORWAY still in debt
{NORWAY_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, NORWAY got money
{NORWAY_MDEBT_TITLE}NORWAY got Money

{IRELAND_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, IRELAND spent too much on the army
{IRELAND_IDEBT_TITLE}IRELAND in debt
{IRELAND_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, IRELAND can continue to recruit now
{IRELAND_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}IRELAND back on track
{IRELAND_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, IRELAND still in debt
{IRELAND_SDEBT_TITLE}IRELAND still in debt
{IRELAND_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, IRELAND got money
{IRELAND_MDEBT_TITLE}IRELAND got Money

{LITHUANIA_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, LITHUANIA spent too much on the army
{LITHUANIA_IDEBT_TITLE}LITHUANIA in debt
{LITHUANIA_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, LITHUANIA can continue to recruit now
{LITHUANIA_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}LITHUANIA back on track
{LITHUANIA_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, LITHUANIA still in debt
{LITHUANIA_SDEBT_TITLE}LITHUANIA still in debt
{LITHUANIA_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, LITHUANIA got money
{LITHUANIA_MDEBT_TITLE}LITHUANIA got Money

{NOVGOROD_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, NOVGOROD spent too much on the army
{NOVGOROD_IDEBT_TITLE}NOVGOROD in debt
{NOVGOROD_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, NOVGOROD can continue to recruit now
{NOVGOROD_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}NOVGOROD back on track
{NOVGOROD_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, NOVGOROD still in debt
{NOVGOROD_SDEBT_TITLE}NOVGOROD still in debt
{NOVGOROD_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, NOVGOROD got money
{NOVGOROD_MDEBT_TITLE}NOVGOROD got Money

{TUAREG_IDEBT_BODY}Oh no, TUAREG spent too much on the army
{TUAREG_IDEBT_TITLE}TUAREG in debt
{TUAREG_DEBT_FREE_BODY}Oh yay, TUAREG can continue to recruit now
{TUAREG_DEBT_FREE_TITLE}TUAREG back on track
{TUAREG_SDEBT_BODY}Oh no, TUAREG still in debt
{TUAREG_SDEBT_TITLE}TUAREG still in debt
{TUAREG_MDEBT_BODY}Oh yay, TUAREG got money
{TUAREG_MDEBT_TITLE}TUAREG got Money

{NW_PLAGUE1_BODY}With the arrival of the Europeans in the New World, they brought an invisible threat. Smallpox ravage through the native population of the Aztecs, and decimate them by the millions. Dead bodys pile up in the streets, entire families find their graves in their houses. An entire culture is about to disappear.
{NW_PLAGUE1_TITLE}Smallpox in North America

{NW_PLAGUE2_BODY}The discovery of the New World and the Aztec Empire by the Europeans, braught death upon the mighty native culture. What no European army could easily achive, the smallpox did. Through the well developed road system, the smallpox spread like wildfire and ate its way through an entire polulation. Will the Aztecs have the strenght to rise again?
{NW_PLAGUE2_TITLE}Smallpox in the Aztec Empire

{TEST_BODY}The New World is ravaged by a plague. Victims die a gruesome, feaverish death. The indigenous people perish in the millions.
{TEST_TITLE}Test Trigger

{APACHEAN_CONTACTED_BODY}It seems North America is already dominated by native civilizations. 
Mostly inhabited by nomadic tribes, that roam the vast land. Those seemingly savage people have a rich culture and will fight for their land with bloody ferocity.
{APACHEAN_CONTACTED_TITLE}North America Inhabited

{AZUMI_CONTACTED_BODY}There are some things you should do and some things you should not. Knocking at the gates of Azumi's Empire is like running across an open field, in plate armour, shouting "Thor is a bloody idiot", during a perfect thunderstorm. Let's hope, The Minor God of Cookies is in a good mood...  
{AZUMI_CONTACTED_TITLE}Empire of Azumi



{SCOTLAND_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{SCOTLAND_RISES_TITLE}Scotland Rises

{IRELAND_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{IRELAND_RISES_TITLE}Ireland Rises

{ENGLAND_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{ENGLAND_RISES_TITLE}England Rises

{FRANCE_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{FRANCE_RISES_TITLE}France Rises

{SPAIN_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{SPAIN_RISES_TITLE}Spain Rises

{PORTUGAL_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{PORTUGAL_RISES_TITLE}Portugal Rises

{MOORS_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{MOORS_RISES_TITLE}Moors Rise

{TUAREG_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{TUAREG_RISES_TITLE}Baghdads Rise

{EGYPT_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{EGYPT_RISES_TITLE}Egypt Rises

{TURKS_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{TURKS_RISES_TITLE}Turks Rise

{BYZANTIUM_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{BYZANTIUM_RISES_TITLE}Byzantium Rises

{RUSSIA_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{RUSSIA_RISES_TITLE}Russia Rises

{NOVGOROD_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{NOVGOROD_RISES_TITLE}Novgorod Rises

{LITHUANIA_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{LITHUANIA_RISES_TITLE}Lithuania Rises

{NORWAY_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{NORWAY_RISES_TITLE}Norway Rises

{DENMARK_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{DENMARK_RISES_TITLE}Denmark Rises

{MILAN_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{MILAN_RISES_TITLE}Milan Rises

{SICILY_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{SICILY_RISES_TITLE}Sicily Rises

{VENICE_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{VENICE_RISES_TITLE}Venice Rises

{POLAND_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{POLAND_RISES_TITLE}Poland Rises

{HUNGARY_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{HUNGARY_RISES_TITLE}Hungary Rises

{HRE_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{HRE_RISES_TITLE}Holy Roman Empire Rises

{APACHEAN_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{APACHEAN_RISES_TITLE}Apachean Rise

{AZTECS_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{AZTECS_RISES_TITLE}Aztecs Rise

{AZUMI_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{AZUMI_RISES_TITLE}Khwarazmians Rise

{TIMURIDS_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{TIMURIDS_RISES_TITLE}Cumans Rise

{DAMASCUS_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{DAMASCUS_RISES_TITLE}Damascenes Rise

{MONGOLS_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{MONGOLS_RISES_TITLE}Mongols Rise

{CILICIA_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{CILICIA_RISES_TITLE}Armenians of Cilicia Rise

{PAPAL_STATES_RISES_BODY}From the ashes of their homelands, the people have risen against foreign rulers. In a swift strike they have taken a city to reclaim what is rightfully theirs.
{PAPAL_STATES_RISES_TITLE}Papal States Rise



{SPANISH_INQUISITION_BODY}The Tribunal of the Holy Office of the Inquisition (Spanish: Tribunal del Santo Oficio de la Inquisición), commonly known as the Spanish Inquisition (Inquisición española), was established in 1478 by Catholic Monarchs Ferdinand II of Aragon and Isabella I of Castile. It was intended to maintain Catholic orthodoxy in their kingdoms and to replace the Medieval Inquisition, which was under Papal control. It became the most substantive of the three different manifestations of the wider Catholic Inquisition along with the Roman Inquisition and Portuguese Inquisition. The "Spanish Inquisition" may be defined broadly, operating "in Spain and in all Spanish colonies and territories, which included the Canary Islands, the Spanish Netherlands, the Kingdom of Naples, and all Spanish possessions in North, Central, and South America. According to modern estimates, around 150,000 were prosecuted for various offenses during the three centuries of duration of the Spanish Inquisition, out of which between 3,000 and 5,000 were executed.
{SPANISH_INQUISITION_TITLE}Unexpected Spanish Inquisition

{SCIENCE_BACON_BODY}Roger Bacon a Franciscan friar who placed considerable emphasis on the study of nature through empiricism finished his Opus Majus. While faculties of the time were largely limited to addressing disputes on the known texts of Aristotle, Bacon engaged in a wide-ranging consideration of the state of knowledge in his era. In 1267 or '68, Bacon sent the Pope his Opus Majus, which presented his views on how to incorporate Aristotelian logic and science into a new theology, supporting the approach against the "sentence method" then fashionable.
{SCIENCE_BACON_TITLE}Doctor Mirabilis

{MARCO_POLO_BODY}An italian merchant, by the name of Marco Polo returned to Venice with many riches and a story beyond belief. 24 years prior he (at the age of 17), together with his uncle and father, set off to Asia. True or not, his adventures in China captivate a great audience and will most certainly spread throughout Europe.
{MARCO_POLO_TITLE}Marvels of the World

{PRESTER_JOHN_BODY}Throughout Europe there is word of a powerful christian King in the far east, that could come to aid the catholic nations of Europe in their struggle for the Holy Land. \n\n ...Should you desire to learn the greatness and excellency of our Exaltedness and of the land subject to our sceptre, then hear and believe: I, Presbyter Johannes, the Lord of Lords, surpass all under heaven in virtue, in riches, and in power; seventy-two kings pay us tribute ... In the three Indies our Magnificence rules, and our land extends beyond India, where rests the body of the holy apostle Thomas; it reaches towards the sunrise over the wastes, and it trends toward deserted Babylon near the Tower of Babel. Seventy-two provinces, of which only a few are Christian, serve us. Each has its own king, but all are tributary to us... \n\n ...When we go to war, we have fourteen golden and bejewelled crosses borne before us instead of banners. Each of these crosses is followed by ten thousand horsemen and one hundred thousand foot soldiers, fully armed, without reckoning those in charge of the luggage and provision... 
{PRESTER_JOHN_TITLE}A simple letter

{CANTERBURY_TALES_BODY}A writer by the name of Geoffrey Chaucer wrote a collection of tales in middle english. Time will tell, if this proves popular... \n\n In th'olde dayes of the Kyng Arthour, \n\n Of which that Britons speken greet honour, \n\n All was this land fulfild of fayerye. \n\n The elf-queene, with hir joly compaignye, \n\n 	Daunced ful ofte in many a grene mede. \n\n This was the olde opinion, as I rede; \n\n 	I speke of manye hundred yeres ago. \n\n But now kan no man se none elves mo, \n\n 	For now the grete charitee and prayeres \n\n Of lymytours and othere hooly freres, \n\n That serchen every lond and every streem, \n\n As thikke as motes in the sonne-beem,...
{CANTERBURY_TALES_TITLE}Tales of Caunterbury

{NIBELUNGENLIED_BODY}The Nibelungenlied a well known and popular saga of old times, was written down by an unknown author and is immensely popular throughout the german speaking realms... \n\n Full many a wonder is told us in stories old, \n\n of heroes worthy of praise, of hardships dire, \n\n of joy and feasting, of weeping and of wailing; \n\n of the fighting of bold warriors, now ye may hear wonders told. 
{NIBELUNGENLIED_TITLE}Heroes Worthy of Praise

{MUSIC_NOTE_BODY}German music theorist Franco of Cologne has written a treatise that suggests that individual notes could have their own durations independent of context, in which the length of a musical note is denoted by the shape of that note. Time will tell, if the idea lasts.
{MUSIC_NOTE_TITLE}Ars cantus mensurabilis

{CATHAR_MASSACRE_BODY}"Caedite eos. Novit enim Dominus qui sunt eius." - \n\n "Kill them. For the Lord knows who are His." \n\n A devastating strike against the Cathar heretics. Arnaud-Amaury, leader of the crusader army, wrote to the Pope: \n\n "Today your Holiness, twenty thousand heretics were put to the sword, regardless of rank, age, or sex." \n\n "The permanent population of Béziers at that time was then probably no more than 5,000, but local refugees seeking shelter within the city walls could conceivably have increased the number to 20,000."  
{CATHAR_MASSACRE_TITLE}Caedite eos

{CATHAR_BURN_BODY}The Cathar Church, albeit under high pressure, was still able to operate and oppose the terror of the Inquisition that pervaded the Languedoc. This leading to the siege of Montségur, "the seat and head" (domicilium et caput) of the Cathar Church. \n\n After nine month, the Cathars surrendered. All the people in the castle were allowed to leave except those who would not renounce their Cathar faith, primarily the perfecti. This group of 210 left the castle and went down to the place where the wood for the pyre had been erected. No stakes were needed: they mounted the pyre and perished voluntarily in the flames.
{CATHAR_BURN_TITLE}Field of the Burned

{FOOTLOOSE_BODY}Groups of people dancing erratically, sometimes thousands at a time. The mania affected men, women, and children who danced until they collapsed from exhaustion. The "Dancing Mania" had now one of the biggest outbreaks in Aachen in the Holy Roman Empire and spread throughout the land. The cause still remains unknown.
{FOOTLOOSE_TITLE}Footloose 

{HUSSITES_UPRISING_BODY}The Council of Constance lured Jan Hus, who fought for a reformation of the church, in with a letter of indemnity, then tried him for heresy and put him to death by burning at the stake. The treatment of Hus is felt to be a disgrace inflicted upon the whole country and his death was seen as a criminal act. Severe unrest will surely follow.
{HUSSITES_UPRISING_TITLE}Bohemian peace at stake  

{JERUSALEM_CHRISTENDOM_CAPTURED_BODY}By the Grace of God, those who went forth in the name our Lord have captured Jerusalem. Thus the Holy city has been triumphantly reclaimed in the name of Christ. All of Christendom will rejoice, for God's Children may now find salvation in the Kingdom of Heaven.
{JERUSALEM_CHRISTENDOM_CAPTURED_TITLE}Jerusalem Captured  

{JERUSALEM_ISLAM_CAPTURED_BODY}Today the followers of the Prophet Mohammed rejoice. For Muslim armies have captured the Holy city of Jerusalem.
{JERUSALEM_ISLAM_CAPTURED_TITLE}Jerusalem Captured  

{CONSTANTINOPLE_LATIN_CAPTURED_BODY}Constantinople has fallen into the Hands of the Latins. \n\n Only time will tell, if it is for the better or for the worse.   
{CONSTANTINOPLE_LATIN_CAPTURED_TITLE}Constantinople Captured  

{CONSTANTINOPLE_BYZANTIUM_CAPTURED_BODY}Today the Byzantines have retaken the city of Constantinople. \n\n Once again becoming the seat of the Emperor and reestablishing it's power.
{CONSTANTINOPLE_BYZANTIUM_CAPTURED_TITLE}Constantinople Retaken  

{CONSTANTINOPLE_ISLAM_CAPTURED_BODY}Today the followers of the Prophet Mohammed rejoice. For Muslim armies have captured the Red Apple of Bosporus. \n\n Now the mighty muslim armies may lie their gaze to Europe.
{CONSTANTINOPLE_ISLAM_CAPTURED_TITLE}Constantinople Captured  

{VIENNA_ISLAM_CAPTURED_BODY}Today the followers of the Prophet Mohammed rejoice. For Muslim armies have captured Vienna and established another foothold in the heart of Latin Lands \n\n It seems that nothing is going to stop them now.
{VIENNA_ISLAM_CAPTURED_TITLE}Vienna Captured  

{ROME_CHRISTENDOM_CAPTURED_BODY}Today the Eternal city of Rome was captured by a christian force. \n\n Time will tell, if it is for the better or for the worse.
{ROME_CHRISTENDOM_CAPTURED_TITLE}Rome Captured  

{ROME_BYZANTIUM_CAPTURED_BODY}Today the Eternal city of Rome was captured by the Byzantines. \n\n Maybe the Roman Empire will rise anew.
{ROME_BYZANTIUM_CAPTURED_TITLE}Rome Captured  

{ROME_ISLAM_CAPTURED_BODY}Today the followers of the Prophet Mohammed rejoice. For Muslim armies have captured the Eternal city of Rome.
{ROME_ISLAM_CAPTURED_TITLE}Rome Captured  

{MEKKA_CHRISTENDOM_CAPTURED_BODY}Today the Holy City of Mecca was captured by a christian force. \n\n Time will tell, if it is for the better or for the worse.
{MEKKA_CHRISTENDOM_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mecca Captured  

{BALAGSUN_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}The Mongols called it Gobalik ("pretty city"). \n\n Now the city and it's people are under the Khan's rule. \n\n Plundered: 1.500 Florin.
{BALAGSUN_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Balasagun   

{TASHKENT_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}Before it was part of the possessions of various Muslim ruling lines, now it has fallen to the Mongols. \n\n Plundered: 3.000 Florin. 
{TASHKENT_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Tashkent   

{SAMARKAND_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}Although the Khan "did not disturb the inhabitants in any way", but according to Juvaini he killed all who took refuge in the citadel and the mosque, pillaged the city completely and conscripted 30,000 young men along with 30,000 craftsmen. \n\n Plundered: 5.000 Florin. \n\n Kings Purse Incremented: 500 Florin. \n\n Conscripted: 2 Mongol Archer Cavalry
{SAMARKAND_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Samarkand   

{BUCHARA_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}The Khan besieged Bukhara for fifteen days. According to Juvaini, after the Khan took Bukhara "he contented himself with looting and slaughter only once and did not go to the extreme of a general massacre" as he did in Khorasan, although most of the city burned. He chose a moderate path between mercy and punishment because the population readily submitted while the garrison in the citadel resisted. Although he spared most adults, the Khan killed 30,000 Qangli Turks who were "taller than the butt of a whip" on account of their loyalty to the Sultan, then conscripted all remaining able-bodied men into service. \n\n Plundered: 3.000 Florin. \n\n Conscripted: 2 Spear Milita
{BUCHARA_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Buchara   

{MERV_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}"The Mongols ordered that, apart from four hundred artisans. .., the whole population, including the women and children, should be killed, and no one, whether woman or man, be spared. To each [Mongol soldier] was allotted the execution of three or four hundred Persians. So many had been killed by nightfall that the mountains became hillocks, and the plain was soaked with the blood of the mighty." \n\n Plundered: 3.000 Florin. 
{MERV_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Merv   

{URGENCH_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}As usual, the artisans were sent back to Mongolia, young women and children were given to the Mongol soldiers as slaves, and the rest of the population was massacred. The Persian scholar Juvayni states that 50,000 Mongol soldiers were given the task of executing twenty-four Urgench citizens each, which would mean that 1.2 million people were killed. While this is almost certainly an exaggeration, the sacking of Urgench is considered one of the bloodiest massacres in human history. \n\n Plundered: 6.000 Florin. 
{URGENCH_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Urgench   

{NISHAPUR_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}Nishapur was besieged and sacked, and a great number of its inhabitants killed and beheaded. Their skulls were reputedly piled in pyramids by the Mongols. \n\n Plundered: 3.000 Florin. \n\n Kings Purse Incremented: 250 Florin. \n\n Conscripted: 2 Mongolian Infantry - 1 Nomad Light Lancer
{NISHAPUR_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Nishapur   

{HERAT_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}"If any one ask thee which is the pleasantest of cities, Thou mayest answer him aright that it is Herāt. For the world is like the sea, and the province of Khurāsān like a pearl-oyster therein, The city of Herāt being as the pearl in the middle of the oyster." \n\n The Great Khan took and destroyed the city. \n\n Plundered: 1.500 Florin. \n\n Conscripted: 2 Dismounted Light Lancers
{HERAT_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Herat   

{RAYY_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}A great city of Persia has fallen into the hands of the Mongols. \n\n Plundered: 3.000 Florin. \n\n Conscripted: 2 Mongol Heavy Archers - 1 Mongol Dismounted Heavy Archers
{RAYY_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Rayy   

{ISFAHAN_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}The inhabitants of Isfahan have been put to the sword. Rašid-al-Din Fażl-Allāh reports: A massacre like none before. \n\n Plundered: 3.000 Florin \n\n Kings Purse Incremented: 250 Florin
{ISFAHAN_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Isfahan   

{BAGHDAD_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}"They swept through the city like hungry falcons attacking a flight of doves, or like raging wolves attacking sheep, with loose reins and shameless faces, murdering and spreading terror...beds and cushions made of gold and encrusted with jewels were cut to pieces with knives and torn to shreds. Those hiding behind the veils of the great Harem were dragged...through the streets and alleys, each of them becoming a plaything...as the population died at the hands of the invaders." \n\n Plundered: 10.000 Florin. \n\n Kings Purse Incremented: 500 Florin. \n\n Conscripted: 4 Sabadar Militia - 2 Mongol Heavy Lancers
{BAGHDAD_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Baghdad   

{ALEPPO_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}For six days the city was under siege. Assisted by catapults and mangonels, Mongol, Armenian and Frankish forces overran the entire city, except for the citadel which held out until 25 February and was demolished following its capitulation. The ensuing massacre, that lasted six days, was methodical and thorough, in which nearly all Muslims and Jews were killed, though most of the women and children were sold into slavery. Also included in the destruction, was the burning of the Great Mosque of Aleppo. \n\n Plundered: 5.000 Florin. \n\n Conscripted: 2 Mongol Infantry - 2 Dismounted Heavy Lancers
{ALEPPO_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Aleppo   

{DAMASCUS_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}The mighty Damascus has fallen by the hands of the Great Khan. \n\n Plundered: 5.000 Florin. \n\n Kings Purse Incremented: 250 Florin. \n\n Conscripted: 4 Sabadar Militia - 2 Mongol Heavy Lancers
{DAMASCUS_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Damascus   

{JERUSALEM_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}"The messengers that Sir Edward and the Christians had sent to the Tartars to ask for help came back to Acre, and they did so well that they brought the Tartars with them, and raided all the land of Antioch, Aleppo, Haman and La Chamele, as far as Caesarea the Great. And they killed all the Sarazins they found." \n\n Plundered: 2.500 Florin. 
{JERUSALEM_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Jerusalem   

{MOSUL_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}"See the use of the stars," said Nassir ud din, " they announce what will happen, and those who know can take precaution and are not panic-stricken as those who are taken by surprise." The Khan spared most of Mosuls people, as he needed their troops for further conquests. \n\n Plundered: 1.000 Florin. \n\n Conscripted: 2 Dismounted Light Lancers - 4 Mongol Foot Archers - 2 Nomad Light Lancers - 2 Mongol Horse Archers
{MOSUL_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Mosul   

{YEREVAN_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}The Great Khan has subjugated the Armenian Princes. The fresh troops will bolster his ranks. \n\n Plundered: 2.500 Florin. \n\n Conscripted: 2 Armenian Archers - 2 Armenian Knights
{YEREVAN_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Yerevan   

{TBILISI_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}The Great Khan has subjugated the Georgian King. The fresh troops will bolster his ranks. \n\n Plundered: 2.500 Florin. \n\n Conscripted: 2 Armenian Archers - 2 Armenian Knights
{TBILISI_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Tbilisi   

{BULGAR_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}The Great Khan has subjugated the Volga Bulgarians. The fresh troops will bolster his ranks. \n\n Plundered: 2.500 Florin. \n\n Kings Purse Incremented: 500 Florin. \n\n Conscripted: 4 Cuman Horse Archers
{BULGAR_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Bulgar   

{ASTRACHAN_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}The Great Khan has subjugated the Cumans and gained a rich trading city. The fresh troops will bolster his ranks. \n\n Plundered: 3000 Florin. \n\n Conscripted: 2 Cuman Horse Archers
{ASTRACHAN_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Astrakhan   

{SARKEL_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}The Great Khan has subjugated the Cumans and gained a fortress. The fresh troops will bolster his ranks. \n\n Plundered: 1500 Florin. \n\n Conscripted: 2 Cuman Horse Archers
{SARKEL_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Sarkel 

{RYAZAN_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}"Those sovereigns … were of Christ-loving lineage, brother-loving, fair of face, bright-eyed, dread of countenance, immeasurably brave, light of heart, kind to their boyars, welcoming to guests, diligent to the church, quick to feast, ready for their sovereign’s amusements, skilled in warfare, and majestic before their brothers and envoys. They had a manly mind, dwelt in truth, and observed purity of soul and body without sin..." \n\n "There was none left to groan and cry"  \n\n Plundered: 3000 Florin. 
{RYAZAN_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Ryazan  

{WORONESCH_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}The Great Khan has subjugated the Pechengs and gained a city. \n\n Plundered: 1500 Florin. 
{WORONESCH_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Voronezh  

{CAFFA_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}The Genoese merchants flee in terror and burn their own city to the ground. \n\n Plundered: 2500 Florin. 
{CAFFA_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Caffa  

{MOSCOW_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}The Rus princes lose one of their valued cities to the Great Khan. A key to the Volga-Bulgarian trade. \n\n Plundered: 3000 Florin. 
{MOSCOW_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Rostov  

{KIEV_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}"Kiev has been reduced from a great and populous city to almost nothing. Scarcely 200 houses remained." \n\n Plundered: 10.000 Florin. \n\n Kings Purse Incremented: 500 Florin. \n\n Conscripted: 4 Sabadar Militia
{KIEV_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Kiev  

{TSCHERNIHIW_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}"Chernigov has fallen to the Great Khan and suffered the fate of cities before her." \n\n Plundered: 5.000 Florin. \n\n Kings Purse Incremented: 250 Florin. \n\n Conscripted: 2 Nomad Light Lancers - 2 Mongol Horse Archers
{TSCHERNIHIW_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Chernigov  

{HALYCH_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}"See the people of Halych. How they have fallen into the Great Khans hands, to do with them as he pleases." \n\n Plundered: 3.000 Florin. \n\n Conscripted: 4 Mongol Infantry
{HALYCH_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Halych  

{CRACOW_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}"Even the Saint Mary's trumpets call could not save the people of Cracow, that was pillaged and burned to the ground." \n\n Plundered: 5.000 Florin. \n\n Conscripted: 2 Dismounted Heavy Lancers
{CRACOW_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Cracow  

{BRESLAU_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}The Great Khan opened the gate to the German lands. \n\n Plundered: 2.500 Florin. 
{BRESLAU_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Breslau  

{BUDAPEST_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}The Hungarian Planes are now under the controll of the great Khan. \n\n Plundered: 5.000 Florin. 
{BUDAPEST_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Budapest  

{VIENNA_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}The Mongolian armies have crossed the Danube River and Viennas citizens have been put to the sword. \n\n Plundered: 10.000 Florin. 
{VIENNA_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Vienna  

{CAIRO_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}The heart of islamic Egypt has fallen to the mighty Khan. \n\n Plundered: 10.000 Florin. 
{CAIRO_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Cairo  

{ROME_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}The eternal city is now part of the ever growing empire of the Mongol Khan. \n\n Plundered: 10.000 Florin. 
{ROME_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Rome  

{CONSTANTINOPLE_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}The great City of East and West was taken by the Mongol Great Khan. Her riches plundered and the people enslaved or put to the sword. \n\n Plundered: 10.000 Florin. 
{CONSTANTINOPLE_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Constantinople  

{NOVGOROD_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}The mighty city of Novgorod is under Mongol control. The riches of the Baltic trade routes now bolster the relentless war machine of the Great Khan. \n\n Plundered: 7.500 Florin. 
{NOVGOROD_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Capture Novgorod  

{ONGUD_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}The Mongol tribe of the Ongud now serve the Great Khan \n\n Plundered: 2.000 Florin. \n\n Kings Purse Incremented: 250 Florin. \n\n Conscripted: 4 Mongol Horse Archers
{ONGUD_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Subjugate the Ongud  

{OIRAT_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}The Mongol tribe of the Oirat now serve the Great Khan \n\n Plundered: 2.000 Florin. \n\n Kings Purse Incremented: 250 Florin. \n\n Conscripted: 4 Mongol Horse Archers
{OIRAT_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Subjugate the Oirat  

{NAIMAN_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_BODY}The Mongol tribe of the Naiman now serve the Great Khan \n\n Plundered: 2.000 Florin. \n\n Kings Purse Incremented: 250 Florin. \n\n Conscripted: 4 Mongol Horse Archers
{NAIMAN_MONGOLS_CAPTURED_TITLE}Mongols Subjugate the Naiman  

{UNIFICATION_MONGOLS_BODY}The Mongol tribes of the great steppes are now unified under one Great Khan. \n\n Plundered: 2.000 Florin. 
{UNIFICATION_MONGOLS_TITLE}The Mongol Tribes are unified   

{NORSE_QUESTION_BODY}Now that you have taken the British Isles and fullfilled your forefathers destiny, your northern brothers want to join your realm and the way of the old norse gods. \n\n Will you let them?
{NORSE_QUESTION_TITLE}The North Remembers   

